[How To Prepare For Your Google Interview
Coding]
You've done it.
You've landed an on-site
interview with Google.
Congratulations!
My fellow Googlers
and I would like to share
our tips and advice on how to prepare.
In this video, we'll cover
communication and collaboration,
creating algorithms
and using data structures,
writing clean and structured code,
testing and error checking,
and overall best practices.
Communication and collaboration
are incredibly important
in the work we do here at Google.
And that's because it's key
to how we approach developing
and building our products.
In your interview, it's important
to demonstrate those qualities.
Understanding a problem,
designing a solution,
and writing code are all
valuable parts of the interview process.
We want you to think out loud.
We don't just want to see the final code.
We want to understand
how you arrived at it.
Google is a collaborative workplace
where projects are planned
and executed by teams.
Those teams have a mission
to work together to solve big,
often ambiguous problems,
not just write code.
And those problems can
have multiple valid solutions.
So, tell us your plan
on how to solve these problems
and be sure to ask questions.
And remember, we're not
looking for one specific answer.
Some of the problems you'll
encounter during your interview
will be deliberately underspecified.
We leave those questions open ended
because real engineering problems
require you to dig deeper.
[2. Algorithms and Data Structures]
At Google, we deal with planet-scale data
and compute systems every day.
Simply identifying a solution
isn't always enough.
The code we write needs
to be fast enough to respond to users
and make efficient use
of our resources.
You should have a strong understanding
of commonly used algorithms
and data structures
to do just that.
When you're presented with a problem,
it's probably a good idea
to outline the algorithm
and discuss it with your interviewer
before you jump into the coding.
It will give you an opportunity
to refine and improve your solution
collaboratively with your interviewer.
Understanding the computational complexity
of your solution is also important.
Remember, you don't have to come up
with the optimal solution up front.
Iterating to improve your solution
can be a valuable part of the process.
You're also going to want to use
appropriate algorithms
and data structures.
You should have a strong
fundamental understanding
of commonly used data structures like
arrays, linked lists, stacks, and queues.
You'll want to know sets, maps,
trees, heaps, and graphs as well.
It's also essential to know
which algorithms tend to go along
with each data structure.
Algorithms that are used to
solve Google problems typically include:
sorting, searching, and binary search.
You should also be familiar
with divide-and-conquer,
dynamic programming and memorization,
greedy algorithms, and recursion.
And be sure to brush up on algorithms
linked to specific data structures
like graph traversal.
You won't be expected to answer
questions requiring some obscure
and highly domain-specific algorithm.
When you're working out
the requirements of an algorithm,
this could also be the perfect time
to think of good test inputs.
[3. Coding]
At Google, developers may
work across different platforms,
but the foundational knowledge required
to perform their job function is the same.
Candidates will be expected
to write idiomatic code
in a programming language
and style they are comfortable with.
Common languages candidates
choose to write code in include
C/C++, Java, Python, JavaScript, or Go.
Choose the language
you are comfortable with.
We are evaluating you
on conceptual understanding.
And we know that if you're fluent
in one programming language,
you could learn another.
We also are not trying to confuse you
with language trivia.
So don't worry too much about
memorization, syntax or punctuation.
We want the substance
of your code to shine through.
[4. Testing and Error Checking]
Google's products
and services are important
for billions of people around the world.
When we make changes,
we need to be confident
that we're not breaking
important existing features.
After you're finished coding
in your interview,
you'll want to run through at least
one or two test cases to check your work.
Good test inputs should exercise
the boundary conditions
in your inputs and your algorithm.
Use simple and compact
sample inputs first
to ensure your code is correct.
And lastly, you may also be asked
to discuss malformed inputs
and how your code handles them.
[5. Best Practices]
Now that you have the focus areas,
here are some overall best practices
to keep in mind
for your actual interview day.
[Explain]
We want to understand
how you think,
so it's important to explain your
thought process during the interview.
We're not only evaluating
your technical ability
but also how you solve problems.
[Clarify]
Many questions will be
deliberately open-ended
to give us an idea
of how you think.
We'd encourage you
to ask for clarification.
[Improve]
And we all know that our first
solution may not be the best one.
So, once you've come up
with an answer to a question,
think about ways to improve upon it.
Let your interviewer know
what you're thinking.
And lastly, practice
on paper or a whiteboard.
You may have the option to use a computer
and/or whiteboard during your interviews,
so you'll want to make sure
you practice for both possible options
and that your code
is easily readable if written.
And those are our tips
to help you prepare
for a coding interview at Google!
If you have any questions
about your upcoming interview,
you can always reach out
to your recruiter.
We're here to help.
And we look forward to seeing you at
one of our offices around the world soon.
[Create for everyone]
[Design for everyone]
[Code for everyone]
[Build for everyone]
[Google
careers.google.com]